A Guide to the Rich Family Papers, 1798-1952
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
- Series II. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts. 1811-1937, Undated., 63 folders.
  - Folder 43. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - Spence and McKee Company. 1830-1860, Undated., 30 items. (Series-folder 2:43)
  - Folder 44. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - Spiller and Phelps Company. 1823-1890, Undated., 29 items. (Series-folder 2:44)
  - Folder 45. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - George Stuart and Company. 1848-1859, Undated., 18 items. (Series-folder 2:45)
  - Folder 46. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - Wood. 1830-1849., 53 items. (Series-folder 2:46)
  - Folder 47. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - Woods. 1850-1859, Undated., 52 items. (Series-folder 2:47)
  - Folder 48. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - Wythe Watering Company. 1841-1888., 17 items. (Series-folder 2:48)
  - Folder 49. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - Mary Polly Thompson Rich. 1860-1874., 54 items. (Series-folder 2:49)
  - Folder 50. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - Mary Polly Thompson Rich. 1875-1877., 40 items. (Series-folder 2:50)
  - Folder 51. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - Mary Polly Thompson Rich. 1878-1879., 45 items. (Series-folder 2:51)
  - Folder 52. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - Mary Polly Thompson Rich. 1880-1883., 50 items. (Series-folder 2:52)
  - Folder 53. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - Mary Polly Thompson Rich. 1884-1885., 44 items. (Series-folder 2:53)
  - Folder 54. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - Mary Polly Thompson Rich. 1886-1889., 50 items. (Series-folder 2:54)
  - Folder 55. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - Mary Polly Thompson Rich. 1890-1894., 43 items. (Series-folder 2:55)
  - Folder 56. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - Mary Polly Thompson Rich. Undated., 30 items. (Series-folder 2:56)
  - Folder 57. Financial Records - Bills and Receipts - Palser Johnson. 1798-1860, Undated, 38 items. (Series-folder 2:57)
  - Folder 58. Financial Records - Promissory Notes. 1820-1830., 16 items. (Series-folder 2:58)
  - Folder 59. Financial Records - Promissory Notes. 1831., 53 items. (Series-folder 2:59)
  - Folder 60. Financial Records - Promissory Notes. 1832-1839., 52 items. (Series-folder 2:60)
  - Folder 61. Financial Records - Promissory Notes. 1840-1844., 43 items. (Series-folder 2:61)
  - Folder 62. Financial Records - Promissory Notes. 1845-1849., 20 items. (Series-folder 2:62)
  - Folder 63. Financial Records - Promissory Notes. 1850-1882, Undated., 44 items. (Series-folder 2:63)
  - Folder 64. Financial Records - Tax Receipts - Wytheville. 1839-1890., 54 items. (Series-folder 2:64)
  - Folder 65. Financial Records - Tax Receipts - Wythe County. 1828-1887., 71 items. (Series-folder 2:65)
  - Folder 66. Financial Records - Tax Receipts - Mary Polly Thompson Rich. 1864-1890., 71 items. (Series-folder 2:66)
  - Folder 67. Financial Records - Tax Receipts - Palser Johnson. 1816-1851., 29 items. (Series-folder 2:67)
- Series III. Legal Records. 1827-1894, Undated., 7 folders.
  - Folder 1. Legal Records - Apprentice Contracts. 1827-1860., 4 items. (Series-folder 3:1)
  - Folder 2. Legal Records - Summons. 1832-1894., 22 items. (Series-folder 3:2)
  - Folder 3. Legal Records -Agreement, Indentures, etc. 1827-1894., 20 items. (Series-folder 3:3)
  - Folder 4. Legal Records - Receipts. 1816-1845., 46 items. (Series-folder 3:4)
  - Folder 5. Legal Records - Receipts. 1846-1877, Undated., 35 items. (Series-folder 3:5)
  - Folder 6. Legal Records - Insurance Policies - Mary Polly Thompson Rich. 1889-1893., 3 items. (Series-folder 3:6)
  - Folder 7. Legal Records - Inventory - Estate of Mary Polly Thompson Rich. 1892., 1 item. (Series-folder 3:7)
- Series IV. Land Records - Deeds. 1810-1889., 2 folders.
  - Folder 1. Land Records - Deeds. 1810-1889., 8 items. (Series-folder 4:1)
  - Folder 2. Land Records - Plats, Surveys, etc. 1818-1861., 6 items. (Series-folder 4:2)
- Series V. Genealogical Records. 1809-1984, Undated., 6 folders.
  - Folder 1. Genealogical Records - Allen Family. 1966, Undated., 2 items. (Series-folder 5:1)
    This folder contains a letter from Harvey Allen of Fort Worth, Texas to P. A. Early of Wytheville, Virginia, dated 16 August 1966, about the Allen family. Also contained in this folder is a sketch of the Allen family by J. Harvey Allen.
  - Folder 2. Genealogical Records - Johnson Family. 1809, Undated., 6 items. (Series-folder 5:2)
    This folder contains an article of the genealogy of Palser Johnson and Mary Thompson by R. P. Johnson, a typescript of the 1809 will of David Yanson, and miscellaneous notes on the Johnson family.
  - Folder 3. Genealogical Records - Rich Family. Undated., 2 items. (Series-folder 5:3)
    This folder contains a memo book and a notebook compiled by P. A. Early Jr. on the Rich family. The folder also contains an article by J. Roderick Moore, Wythe County, Virginia, Punched Tin: Its Influence and Imitators, in The Magazine Antiques, September 1984.
  - Folder 4. Genealogical Records - Rich Family - Notes of P. A. Early Jr. Undated., 9 items. (Series-folder 5:4)
  - Folder 5. Genealogical Records - Rich Family - Notes of Mary B. Kegley. Undated., 55 items. (Series-folder 5:5)
  - Folder 6. Genealogical Records - Williams Family and Rosenheim Family. Undated. (Series-folder 5:6)
- Series VI. Books. 1829-1887, undated., 14 folders.
  - Folder 1. Books - Account Books. 1829-1852., 5 items. (Series-folder 6:1)
    This folder contains five account books: 1839-1852; 1830-1835; 1835-1836; 1836-1837; 1838-1841.
  - Folder 2. Books - Account Books. 1841-1858, Undated., 9 items. (Series-folder 6:2)
    This folder contains 9 accounts books: 1841-1846; 1842-1845; 1847-1850; 1850; 1850-1851; 1853; 1851-1854; 1858; 3 undated books.
  - Folder 3. Books - Ledger. 1832-1833., 74 numbered p.; missing pages and back cover. (Series-folder 6:3)
  - Folder 4. Books - Ledger. 1831-1833., 72 numbered p.; loose pages on p. 13 and p. 36. (Series-folder 6:4)
  - Folder 5. Books - Ledger. 1835-1839., 55 numbered p. (Series-folder 6:5)
  - Folder 6. Books - Ledger. 1836-1840., 28 numbered p.; loose page on p. 2 and p. 16. (Series-folder 6:6)
  - Folder 7. Books - Ledger. 1845-1847., Pages not numbered. (Series-folder 6:7)
  - Folder 8. Books - Ledger. 1847-1849., Pages not numbered. (Series-folder 6:8)
  - Folder 9. Books - Ledger. 1857-1859; 1868-1886., Pages not numbered. (Series-folder 6:9)
  - Folder 10. Books - Ledger. 1874-1887., 234 numbered pages; loose pages on p. 95, p. 129, and p. 229. (Series-folder 6:10)
  - Folder 11. Books - Ledger. 1839-1871., Pages not numbered. (Series-folder 6:11)
  - Folder 12. Books - Miscellaneous ledger pages. Undated., 9 items. (Series-folder 6:12)
  - Folder 13. Books - Ledger. 1840-1845., Pages not numbered; loose front and back cover. (Series-folder 6:13)
  - Folder 14. Books - Ledger. 1834-1839., 59 numbered pages; loose pages on p. 37 and p. 59. (Series-folder 6:14)
- Series VII. Miscellaneous Records. 1834-1891, Undated., 3 folders.
  - Folder 1. Miscellaneous Records. 1834-1891, Undated., 7 items. (Series-folder 7:1)
    This folder contains a photograph of an unidentified male and two applications, dated 16 August 1884 and 28 August 1891, by Mary Polly Thompson Rich for licensing by the Virginia Department of the Revenue for her boarding house. Also enclosed are fine notices issued to Fleming Kean Rich for non-attendance at muster of militia dated May 1834 for Captain Boyd's Company and dated July 1837 for Captain Currin's Troop. Finally notes on the birthdates of William Seavers and daughters of Samuel Hampton complete the folder.
  - Folder 2. Miscellaneous Records - School Reports. 1872., 4 items. (Series-folder 7:2)
    This folder contains a monthly report for Wythe County Public School No. 18 at Speedwell by Bettie P. Williams, 1872 as well as an undated memorandum listing Poor Scholars in Attendance. ALso included in this folder is a list of parents and students for an unknown school and blank report card.
  - Folder 3. Miscellaneous Records - Recipes. Undated., 19 items. (Series-folder 7:3)
- Series VII. Photocopies Rich Papers. 1838-1860., 1 folder.
  - Folder 1. Photocopies of Rich Papers. 1838-1860., 9 items. (Series-folder 8:1)
    This folder contains photocopies of Rich Papers in a private collection. Included are letters (dated 12 June 1847, 17 May 1850, 1 January 1854, and 9 July 1860) from John Rich and Elizabeth Rich of Benton County Arkansas to Fleming Kean Rich. Also included are tax receipts of Palser Johnson (1841, 1843, 1850), receipts of Palser Johnson (1841, 1857), and statement of Palser Johnson in account with R. Gibboney and Company dated 1838.